

ABOUT ME

I am a 12 year Army veteran and computer science student, currently serving as a Lead Incident Manager. With over 7 years of experience in the IT industry, I bring to you superior customer service, expert troubleshooting, and a drive to constantly learn new skills where together, we will achieve more.

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Microsoft Software and Systems Academy | JBLM, WA | 2021 – Present

- Developed multiple applications with C#, Python, and T-SQL to solve various problem solving issues during class projects.
- Developed multiple ethical hacking tools using Python in a virtual environment.

Lead Major Incident Manager/Sr. Engineer

Mindtree Limited | Redmond, WA | 2018 - Present

- Received multiple awards as a Team Influencer and High Performer by operating
 efficiently under high-stress situations during Major Incidents/Outages for
 Microsoft's core services.
- Improved Key Performance Indicators by up to 16% across all deliverables, notably bridge management, incident recordings, and executive-level communications.

Azure Platforms Engineer/Premier Support

Mindtree Limited | Redmond, WA | 2017 - 2018

- Transformed the Azure Platforms Team leadership structure, producing multiple small group leaders and increasing overall management efficiency.
- Received over 97% Customer Satisfaction ratings across all support cases by providing cloud computing solutions to complex issues on the Azure platform.

PROJECTS

SeCure-ity - bit.ly/SeCure-ity

Python | Kali-Linux | Metasploitable | Virtualization

- Created a collection of cyber security tools using Python:
 - o MAC Address Changer
 - o Vulnerability Scanner (in progress)
 - Network Scanner (in progress)
 - Website Crawler (in progress)

Crap-a-Dappa – bit.ly/Play-Craps

C#

• Developed a console application where users could learn how to play the Craps dice game.

- 253.355.2924
- john.s.cruz@outlook.com
- Greater Seattle Area
- LinkedIn.com/in/johnscruz
- github.com/Cruz-S13

SKILLS

C# Leadership Development
Python Change Management
TSQL C-Suite Communications
HTML Business Insights
CSS3 Azure laaS Platform

JavaScript Infrastructure Management
Power BI Major Incident Management

AWARDS

MTA 98-361: Software Development

Fundamentals

Intro to Python: University of Michigan

ITIL Foundations

SpotOn Award - Influencing: Mindtree Ltd.
SpotOn Award - A Team: Mindtree Ltd.

EDUCATION

Certificate of Computer Science

Saint Martin's University Projected Graduation - 2021

BAS: Network Security Administration

Green River College 2016 - 2017

AAS: Systems and Network Security

Clover Park Technical College

2014 - 2016